<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Punjab Tourism</string>
    <string name="golden_temple_desc">Sri Harmandir Sahib (Golden Temple)
The Golden temple is located in the holy city of the Sikhs, Amritsar. The Golden temple is famous for its full golden dome, it is one of the most sacred pilgrim spots for Sikhs. The Mandir is built on a 67-ft square of marble and is a two storied structure. Maharaja Ranjit Singh had the upper half of the building built with approximately 400 kg of gold leaf.

The Golden Temple is surrounded by a number of other famous temples like the Durgiana Temple. The fourth Guru of Sikhs, Guru Ram Das, who had initially constructed a pool here, founded Amritsar, which houses the Golden Temple or Harmandir Sahib. It is here that Sage Valmiki wrote the epic, Ramayana. Rama and Sita are believed to have spent their fourteen-year exile in Amritsar, the epicenter of Sikhism. To the south of the temple is a garden, and the tower of Baba Atal. The Central Sikh Museum is atop the Clock Tower. The ‘Guru Ka Langar’ offers free food to around 20,000 people everyday. The number shoots up to 100,000 on special occasions. A visitor must cover his / her head before entering the temple premises.

The Granth Sahib is kept in the Temple during the day and is kept in the Akal Takht or Eternal Throne in the night. The Akal Takht also houses the ancient weapons used by the Sikh warriors. Guru Hargobind established it. The rugged old Jubi Tree in the north west corner of the compound is believed to possess special powers. It was planted 450 years ago, by the Golden Temple’s first high priest, Baba Buddha. Guru-ka-Langar or the communal canteen is towards the eastern entrance of the temple complex, and it provides free food to all visitors, regardless of colour, creed, caste or gender. Visitors to the Golden Temple must remove their shoes and cover their heads before entering the temple. The temple is less crowded in the early mornings on weekends.</string>

<string name="durgiana_temple">The Shri Durgiana Mandir is a Hindu temple situated in the city of Amritsar in Punjab, India.[1] Though a Hindu temple, its architecture is similar to the Sikh Harmandir Sahib (Golden Temple).[2] The temple derives its name from the Goddess Durga, the chief Goddess who is worshipped here. Murtis of Lakshmi and Vishnu are also located and worshipped in the temple.[3]

Although it is believed that Durgiana Mandir was built in 1921, the temple existed before it was rebuilt in 1921.[citation needed] It is confirmed by record in Amritsar District Gazetteer of 1893, which spoke about the Durgiana Sarovar and "Devi dwara" surrounding it which was visited by Hindu pilgrims</string>

<string name="ram_tirath">Located 12 Km west of Amritsar on Chogawan road, dates back to the period of Ramayana, Rishi Valmiki’s hermitage. The place has an ancient tank and many temples. A hut marks the site where Mata Sita gave birth to Luv &amp; Kush and also, still extant are Rishi Valmiki’s hut and the well with stairs where Mata Sita used to take her bath. The Bedis of Punjab (Guru Nanak Dev, the founder Prophet of Sikhism was a Bedi) trace their descent from Kush and Sodhis (the 10th Prophet of Sikhism, Guru Gobind Singh was a Sodhi) from Luv. A four day fair, since times immemorial is held here starting on the full moon night in November. 16 kilometres west on Choganwan road is Ram Tirath, commemorating Maharishi Valmiki Ji´s heritage.</string>

<string name="wagah_border">The international border between India and Pakistan. The pomp and pageantry of the Beating Retreat and the Change of Guard within handshaking distance of the Indian and Pakistani forces makes for a most charming spectacle. Wagah, an army outpost on Indo-Pak border – between Amritsar and Lahore, is an elaborate complex of buildings, roads and barriers on both sides. The daily highlight is the evening “Beating the Retreat” ceremony. Soldiers from both countries march in perfect drill, going through the steps of bringing down their respective national flags. As the sun goes down, nationalistic fervour rises and lights are switched on marking the end of the day amidst thunderous applause.</string>

    <string name="jallian_wala_bagh">Jallianwala Bagh Massacre, incident on April 13, 1919, in which British troops fired on a large crowd of unarmed Indians in an open space known as the Jallianwala Bagh in Amritsar in the Punjab region (now in Punjab state) of India, killing several hundred people and wounding many hundreds more. It marked a turning point in India’s modern history, in that it left a permanent scar on Indo-British relations and was the prelude to Mohandas (Mahatma) Gandhi’s full commitment to the cause of Indian nationalism and independence from Britain.

During World War I (1914–18) the British government of India enacted a series of repressive emergency powers that were intended to combat subversive activities. By the war’s end, expectations were high among the Indian populace that those measures would be eased and that India would be given more political autonomy. The Montagu-Chelmsford Report, presented to the British Parliament in 1918, did in fact recommend limited local self-government. Instead, however, the government of India passed what became known as the Rowlatt Acts in early 1919, which essentially extended the repressive wartime measures.</string>

    <string name="maharaja_ranjit_singh_meusium">At a distance of 1.5 km from Amritsar Junction and 4 km from Amritsar Golden Temple, Maharaja Ranjit Singh Museum is a popular museum situated in the middle of a beautiful Ram Bagh Garden in Amritsar, Punjab. It is one of the best museums in Punjab and also one of the top tourist attractions in Amritsar. Maharaja Ranjit Singh Museum was originally the summer palace of first king of Sikh Empire, Maharaja Ranjit Singh. Later, it was converted in to museum in 1977 CE. It is a treasure house of the history, art and architecture of the Sikhs of the 18th and the 19th century AD. The museum offers insights into the life of the Sikh monarch Maharaja Ranjit Singh. The Museum displays objects connecting to Maharaja Ranjit Singh such as arms and armour, outstanding paintings and centuries old coins and manuscripts. The paintings displayed in the galleries of the museum showcase the court and camp of the king. Among all the paintings, one that depicts the city of Lahore is most famous. Coins and manuscripts displayed at the museum reflect the spirit of secularism in the king and rich history of Sikh province, respectively. The arms and ammunition section of the Museum shows a rich collection of weapons, which were prevalent among the great warriors of that time. Next to this museum stands the beautiful Maharaja Ranjit Singh Panorama, an eternal visual record which encapsulates the life of the Maharaja.</string>

    <string name="gobindgarh_fort">Gobindgarh Fort is a historic military fort located in the center of the city of Amritsar in the Indian state of Punjab. The Fort was until recently occupied by the Indian Army, but was opened to the public on 10 February 2017. Today the fort is being developed as a museum and theme park, as a repository of Punjab’s history.

Popularly known as the Bhangian da Killa (fort of the Bhangis) taken away during 18th- century from Bhangi Misl of Dhillon Jats sardars.

Maharaja Ranjit Singh conquered Bhangi Misl of Dhillon Jats sardars during 18th-century, and appreciated original name supporting the 10th Sikh guru, Guru Gobind Singh.

Gobindgarh Fort is located on the south west fringe of Amritsar, in a square pattern, with a perimeter of 1,000 m and made up entirely of bricks and lime. The fort had 25 cannons mounted on its ramparts and it remained with the Bhangi rulers till 1805. From the middle of the 19th century until Indian independence in 1947, it was occupied by the British army who made numerous defensive improvements to the fort to take account of technological advances in weaponry.</string>

    <string name="pull_kanjari">Pul Kanjri is a historical site situated 35 km away from Amritsar on Amritsar-Lahore road, near the villages of Dhanoa Khurd and Dhanoa Kalan on the Wagah border. It is one of the heritage sites built by Maharaja Ranjit Singh, where he used to rest while travelling with his troops. During his reign, Pul Kanjari was an important trading centre. The legend has it when Maharaja Ranjit Singh married Begum Gul Bahar, on their way to Lahore they had to cross this canal on Ravi river. People used to cross the canal by foot but Begum Gul Bahar refused to do so. Since Maharaja Ranjit Singh was deeply in love with Begum Gul Bahar, he had a small bridge built for her. Some part of the bridge still exists. It was named Pul Kanjri. It was greatly in news during 1971 war. This fortress also contains a bathing pool, a temple, a Gurudwara and a mosque.

People used to come to Pul Kanjri from far-flung areas, including Amritsar and Lahore, for shopping. The town was inhabited by Arora Sikhs, Muslims and Hindus who lived together until the partition of India. The historical town has been reduced to a tiny village now.[1] The area is located on the present day border of the two states and it was briefly occupied by Pakistan in 1965 and 1971. However, the area was later returned to India as a part of peace treaty between the countries.</string>

</resources>